<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Sensor Mobile</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="config">Settings</string>
    <string name="acercaDe">About</string>
    <string name="inicio">Main screen</string>
    <string name="teoria">Theory</string>
    <string name="explicacion">\nThis application has been designed and developed by:\n\n
\t\tDiego Esteban Moreno\n
\t\tFélix Huete García\n\n
As a final project for the University of Valladolid of Engineering degree in Computer Systems.\n\n

Tutors:\n\n
\t\tMiguel Ángel González Rebollo\n 
\t\tManuel Ángel González Delgado\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionacercade2">The application shows use of the accelerometer, gyroscope, magnetometer, light sensor, proximity sensor and GPS, as well as measurement tool in physics laboratories.\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionacercade">Sensor Mobile is an application designed as display unit of sensors on your Android device.\n</string>
    <string name="idiomas">LANGUAGES</string>
    <string name="medicion">Measurement data</string>
    <string name="aceleracion">Acceleration</string>
    <string name="velocidad">Angular velocity</string>
    <string name="magnetismo">Magnetic flux density</string>
    <string name="sensor">Sensor</string>
    <string name="nombresensor">Name</string>
    <string name="consumo">Power</string>
    <string name="version">Version</string>
    <string name="distribuidor">Vendor</string>
    <string name="empezar">Start</string>
    <string name="continuar">Continue</string>
    <string name="parar">Pause/Stop</string>
    <string name="acelerometro">Accelerometer</string>
    <string name="luminosidad">Light sensor</string>
    <string name="proximidad">Proximity sensor</string>
    <string name="giroscopio">Gyroscope</string>
    <string name="magnetico">Magnetometer</string>
    <string name="compartir">Share</string>
    <string name="guardar">Save (csv)</string>
    <string name="guardado_acelerometro">Accelerometer saved</string>
    <string name="error_guardar">Error saving</string>
    <string name="eje_x">X</string>
    <string name="eje_y">Y</string>
    <string name="eje_z">Z</string>
    <string name="eje_modulo">Module</string>
    <string name="distancia">Distance</string>
    <string name="luminosi">Luminosity</string>
    <string name="unidad_acelerometro">m/s²</string>
    <string name="tiempo">RECORDING TIME</string>
    <string name="frecuencias">SAMPLING FRECUENCY</string>
    <string name="temporizador">TIMER</string>
    <string name="lento">SLOW</string>
    <string name="normal">NORMAL</string>
    <string name="rapido">FAST</string>
    <string name="muyrapido">FASTEST</string>
    <string name="apagado">OFF</string>
    <string name="auto">AUTO</string>
    <string name="espa">SPANISH</string>
    <string name="ingles">ENGLISH</string>
    <string name="frances">FRENCH</string>
    <string name="portugues">PORTUGUESE</string>
    <string name="subidioma">Select the application language.</string>
    <string name="subfrecuencia">Select sampling frequency, number of samples per second.</string>
    <string name="subtemporizador">Select time elapses since enter in the graphic screen until it begins to record.</string>
    <string name="subtiempo">Select recording time.</string>
    <string name="reiniciar">Reset</string>
    <string name="grafica">Graph</string>
    <string name="cargargraficas">Load graph</string>
    <string name="checkAcelerometro">Save data</string>
    <string name="checkGiroscopio">Save data</string>
    <string name="checkMagnetometro">Save data</string>
    <string name="checkLuz">Save data</string>
    <string name="checkProximidad">Save data</string>
    <string name="unidad_giroscopio">rad/s</string>
    <string name="unidad_campo_magnetico">µT</string>
    <string name="unidad_luz">Lux</string>
    <string name="unidad_proximidad">cm</string>
    <string name="guardado_giroscopio">Gyroscope saved</string>
    <string name="guardado_magnetometro">Magnetometer saved</string>
    <string name="guardar_luz">Light sensor saved</string>
    <string name="guardar_proximidad">Proximity sensor saved</string>
    <string name="guardado_gps">GPS saved</string>
    <string name="datosCompartir">No data to share</string>
    <string name="datosGuardar">No data to save</string>
    <string name="tiempoSeg">Time in seconds</string>
    <string name="titulo1">\nABOUT ACCELEROMETER\n</string>
    <string name="explicacion1">It is a device that measures acceleration, rate of change of velocity of an object, and the forces induced by gravity, i.e., allows us to detect the movement and rotation.\n This is measured in meters per second squared (m / s2) or forces g (g).\n</string>
    <string name="titulo2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicacion2">The main constituent is a capacitor, a device that is usually composed of two fixed metal plates facing each other and a dielectric material.\n
One of these plates is mobile. When you apply a force to the device, the capacity will increase or decrease depending on the movement.\n
The energy comes through these plates from the battery device into the capacitor. The dielectric material between these plates will be able to store a charge or another depending on whether the capacitor is higher or lower.\n
This procedure will allow the sensor to measure how much electrical charge (voltage) is stored in the dielectric material and send that information to the microprocessor device to determine the force and acceleration that has been submitted. The microprocessor has recorded the voltage obtained and saved in a database which had already been recorded other voltages, corresponding to a force and to a certain acceleration.\n</string>
    <string name="titulo3">\nPURPOSE OF ACCELEROMETER\n</string>
    <string name="explicacion3">An accelerometer can automatically change the screen orientation and detect vertical or horizontal position of the screen.\n</string>
    <string name="titulo4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicacion4">The accelerometer measures the acceleration applied to the device and its features are summarized in the table.</string>
    <string name="sensores">Sensor device</string>
    <string name="titulogiro1">\nABOUT GYROSCOPE\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongiro1">A gyroscope is a mechanical device that helps us to measure, maintain and change the orientation of a device. I.e., it measures the rotational speed (rad / s).\n</string>
    <string name="titulogiro2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongiro2">It is based on the angular momentum. It uses a micro electromechanical technology (MEMS) with a silicon sensor thanks to special plates that act as capacitors. Intensity changes are converted into digital data and that is what reads the microprocessor.\n
Once the gyroscope sets in motion always maintains the orientation and it is oriented to the true north. The gyro gives us a precise orientation, it indicates the displacement on their axes and gives us the position regarding the exact starting point.\n
MENS (Microelectromechanical Systems, MEMS) refer to the electromechanical technology, their micrometer products and smaller scales (nanometer scale) are merged into nanoelectromechanical systems.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogiro3">PURPOSE OF GYROSCPE\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongiro3">The gyroscope give us the possibility to turn your screen.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogiro4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongiro4">The gyroscope measures the speed of rotation of the device around the x, y, and z axis.The values of the gyro data can be positive or negative. Looking at the origin of a position along the mid-axis positive, if the rotation occurs to the left side around the axis, the value is positive; Otherwise, the value is negative. We can also determine the direction of a gyroscope value.\n</string>
    <string name="titulomagne1">\nABOUT MAGNETOMETER\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionmagne1">It is an electronic component capable of measuring and quantifying the magnetic force of an object. I.e. it measures the magnetic field (µT).\n</string>
    <string name="titulomagne2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionmagne2">The main constituent is an electromagnet with an iron core with a coil of wire wrapped.\n
The magnetism changes depending on the location due to differences in (the magnetosphere) Earth\'s magnetic field and can be caused by the different nature of the rocks. Magnetometers are a frequent instrumental component of spacecraft that explores planets and for geological exploration for anticlinal structures.\n</string>
    <string name="titulomagne3">PURPOSE OF MAGNETOMETER\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionmange3">As well as a compass, it can serve as a metal detector.\n</string>
    <string name="titulomagne4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionmange4">The most important use of the magnetometer (described in table) in Android systems is to implement the compass.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloluz1">\nABOUT LIGHT SENSOR\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionluz1">It is an electronic device that responds to the change in light intensity. These sensors require a transmitter that generates light and a receptor component that receives light generated by the transmitter.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloluz2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionluz2">The light sensor includes a photoelectric transducer to convert the light into an electrical signal and may include electronics for signal conditioning and formatting the compensation signal.\n
The most common light sensor is Light Dependant Resistor. A LDR is basically a resistor that changes its resistance when light intensity changes. There are three types of photoelectric sensors, sensors for light barrier, reflection on mirror or reflection on objects.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloluz3">PURPOSE OF LIGHT SENSOR\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionluz3">Its function is to detect the intensity of the ambience light to adjust the screen brightness.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloluz4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionluz4">The system uses the ambient light sensor, described in the table, to detect the ambience lighting and automatically adjust the screen brightness to the appropriate level.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloprox1">\nABOUT PROXIMITY SENSOR\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionprox1">Se trata de un sensor capaz de medir la distancia entre el móvil y algún otro objeto. El sensor de proximidad se mide en centímetros (cm).\n</string>
    <string name="tituloprox2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionprox2">These proximity sensors are based on an infra-red LED and an IR receiver. How does it work? It emits infra-red light and it detects if there is something very close to the device. In the case of a call, would be the ear.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloprox3">PURPOSE OF PROXIMITY SENSOR\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionprox3">When the device is approached to our ear to answer a call, the device turns off the backlight to save battery.\n
Besides, if we touch the screen by accident while we are on a call, nothing will happen because the proximity sensor locks the screen to prevent such errors.\n
Usually, if the device is dark it is almost imperceptible but if we look to the light we see it, if it has, of course.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloprox4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionprox4">The proximity sensor provides the distance between the device and another object. The device can be used to detect if the user holds the device near (see table); therefore, you can determine if the user is on a call and if the screen can be turned off during the phone call\n</string>
    <string name="titulogps1">\nABOUT GPS\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongps1">Global Navigation Satellite System (GNSS) which allows us to set global position of an object, a person, a vehicle or a ship.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogps2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongps2">The GPS is based on the triangulation, a mathematical principle that determines the exact position of a point knowing the distances from a known location to three points. Three satellites are used to determine the position, speed and height of receiver.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogps3">PURPOSE IF GPS\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongps3">The GPS indicates paths, routes or location.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogps4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongps4">Latitude and longitude.\n</string>
    <string name="gpsoff">GPS off</string>
    <string name="gpsbuscando">Searching GPS</string>
    <string name="gpssignal">GPS signal</string>
    <string name="currentDir">Current Dir</string>
    <string name="fileSize">File size</string>
    <string name="gps">GPS</string>
    <string name="checkGps">Save data</string>
    <string name="latitud">Latitude</string>
    <string name="longitud">Longitude</string>
    <string name="ayuda">Help</string>
    <string name="ayuda11">In the main screen you can choose between:\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda12">Measurement data:\n
\tsensor measures will be showing here.\n
Load graph:\n
 \tEvery graph you have saved are listed in this screen.\n
In the menu you will find SETTINGS button with 4 options:\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda13">Sensor device: list of sensors device.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda14">\t\tName\n
\t\tPowe\n
\t\tVersion\n
\t\tVendor\n
\nSettings: application preferences, which are:\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda15">\n\tLanguage: You can choose Auto, English, Spanish, French or Portuguese.\n
\tBelow settings divider you can see other three options:\n
\t\t\tSampling frequency: number of samples per second.\n
\t\t\tTimer: time elapsed since we enter in the graphic screen until it begins to record.\n
\t\t\tRecording time.\n
About: Information about the application privacy and their developers\n
Help: Manual of the application.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda21">Sensor device and their measures. This screen is divided:\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda22">\nSensor information (buttons):\n
\tAccelerometer\n
\tGyroscope\n
\tMagnetometer\n
\tProximity sensor\n
\tLight sensor\n
\tGPS\n
\nBelow every button information you can see:\n
\tCheckbox save data: if it is checked data will be saved in csv file.\n
\tGraph icone:  Start graph screen where data will be represented.\n
\tMuestra de datos: sensor measures in real time.\n
There are application preferences in this menu:\n
\t\t\tSampling frequency: number of samples per second.\n
\t\t\tTimer: time elapsed since we enter in the graphic screen until it begins to record.\n
\t\t\tRecording time.\n
About: Information about the application privacy and their developers\n
Help: Manual of the application.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda31">Data are represented in this screen.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda32">Screen schema:\n
\tStart button: graph will start.\n
\tBotón Pause/Stop: Stop or pause the data representation.\n
\tReset: will be pressed to start a new representation of the graph.\n
Below these button:\n
\tCheckbox: may be selected depending on what data you want to display.\n
\tREC: green if not checked save data in Measurement Data screen, else this icone is red.\n
\tGPS signal: state of gps (searching or off).\n
\tGraph: the data collected by the device are represented.\n
Once started the representation of measurements, you can switch from one sensor to another, share or save it in CSV format (menu).\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda41">In this screen you can see all files saved. If you select a file it will show the representation of the measurements. If you push for an extended period of time, the file may be sent via the option you want.\n
Once selected if you want to remove from the list to send, press and hold on the same file and remain unchecked.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda42">Multiples files may be selected to send.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda51">The information screens sensor (gyroscope, accelerometer, magnetometer, light sensor, proximity sensor and GPS) shows the explanation of each sensor. Each screen is structured:\n
\tAbout: explanation about the sensor and measuring\n
\tHow it works: explaining the operation of sensor.\n
\tPurpose : sensor utility.\n
\tWhat it measures: measures taken by the sensor on the Android device.\n</string>

</resources>