<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Sensor Mobile</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="config">Settings</string>
    <string name="acercaDe">About</string>
    <string name="inicio">Main screen</string>
    <string name="teoria">Theory</string>
    <string name="explicacion">\nDiseñada y creada por los autores:\n\n
\t\tDiego Esteban Moreno\n
\t\tFélix Huete García\n\n
Como proyecto final de carrera para la Universidad de Valladolid de la titulación Ingeniería Técnica de Informática de Sistemas.\n\n

Como tutores:\n\n
\t\tMiguel Ángel González Rebollo\n 
\t\tManuel Ángel González Delgado.\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionacercade2">La aplicación muestra el uso del acelerómetro, giroscopio, magnetómetro, sensor de luz, sensor aproximación y GPS, además como utensilio de medida en los laboratorios de física.\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionacercade">Sensor Mobile es una aplicación diseñada como un visor y monitor de los sensores de su dispositivo Android.\n</string>
    <string name="idiomas">Languages</string>
    <string name="medicion">Measurement data</string>
    <string name="aceleracion">Acceleration</string>
    <string name="velocidad">Angular velocity</string>
    <string name="magnetismo">Magnetic flux density</string>
    <string name="sensor">Sensor</string>
    <string name="nombresensor">Name</string>
    <string name="consumo">Power</string>
    <string name="version">Version</string>
    <string name="distribuidor">Vendor</string>
    <string name="empezar">Start</string>
    <string name="continuar">Continue</string>
    <string name="parar">Pause/Stop</string>
    <string name="acelerometro">Accelerometer</string>
    <string name="luminosidad">Light sensor</string>
    <string name="proximidad">Proximity sensor</string>
    <string name="giroscopio">Gyroscope</string>
    <string name="magnetico">Magnetometer</string>
    <string name="compartir">Share</string>
    <string name="guardar">Save (csv)</string>
    <string name="guardado_acelerometro">Accelerometer saved</string>
    <string name="error_guardar">Error saving</string>
    <string name="eje_x">X</string>
    <string name="eje_y">Y</string>
    <string name="eje_z">Z</string>
    <string name="eje_modulo">Module</string>
    <string name="distancia">Distance</string>
    <string name="luminosi">Luminosity</string>
    <string name="unidad_acelerometro">m/s²</string>
    <string name="tiempo">RECORDING TIME</string>
    <string name="frecuencias">SAMPLING FRECUENCY</string>
    <string name="temporizador">TIMER</string>
    <string name="infoacelerometro">ABOUT ACCELEROMETER</string>
    <string name="infogiroscopio">ABOUT GYROSCOPE</string>
    <string name="infomagnetico">ABOUT MAGNETOMETER</string>
    <string name="infoproximidad">ABOUT PROXIMITY SENSOR</string>
    <string name="infoluz">ABOUT LIGHT SENSOR</string>
    <string name="reiniciar">Reset</string>
    <string name="modulo">|V|</string>
    <string name="grafica">Graph</string>
    <string name="cargargraficas">Load graph</string>
    <string name="checkAcelerometro">Save data</string>
    <string name="checkGiroscopio">Save data</string>
    <string name="checkMagnetometro">Save data</string>
    <string name="checkLuz">Save data</string>
    <string name="checkProximidad">Save data</string>
    <string name="unidad_giroscopio">rad/s</string>
    <string name="unidad_campo_magnetico">µT</string>
    <string name="unidad_luz">Lux</string>
    <string name="unidad_proximidad">cm</string>
    <string name="guardado_giroscopio">Gyroscope saved</string>
    <string name="guardado_magnetometro">Magnetometer saved</string>
    <string name="guardar_luz">Light sensor saved</string>
    <string name="guardar_proximidad">Proximity sensor saved</string>
    <string name="guardado_gps">GPS saved</string>
    <string name="titulo1">\nABOUT ACCELEROMETER\n</string>
    <string name="explicacion1">It is a device that measures acceleration, rate of change of velocity of an object, and the forces induced by gravity, i.e., allows us to detect the movement and rotation.\n This is measured in meters per second squared (m / s2) or forces g (g).\n</string>
    <string name="titulo2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicacion2">The main constituent is a capacitor, a device that is usually composed of two fixed metal plates facing each other and a dielectric material.\n
One of these plates is mobile. When you apply a force to the device, the capacity will increase or decrease depending on the movement.\n
The energy comes through these plates from the battery device into the capacitor. The dielectric material between these plates will be able to store a charge or another depending on whether the capacitor is higher or lower.\n
This procedure will allow the sensor to measure how much electrical charge (voltage) is stored in the dielectric material and send that information to the microprocessor device to determine the force and acceleration that has been submitted. The microprocessor has recorded the voltage obtained and saved in a database which had already been recorded other voltages, corresponding to a force and to a certain acceleration.\n</string>
    <string name="titulo3">\nPURPOSE OF ACCELEROMETER\n</string>
    <string name="explicacion3">An accelerometer can automatically change the screen orientation and detect vertical or horizontal position of the screen.\n</string>
    <string name="titulo4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicacion4">The accelerometer measures the acceleration applied to the device and its features are summarized in the table.</string>
    <string name="sensores">Sensor device</string>
    <string name="titulogiro1">\nABOUT GYROSCOPE\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongiro1">A gyroscope is a mechanical device that helps us to measure, maintain and change the orientation of a device. I.e., it measures the rotational speed (rad / s).\n</string>
    <string name="titulogiro2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongiro2">It is based on the angular momentum. It uses a micro electromechanical technology (MEMS) with a silicon sensor thanks to special plates that act as capacitors. Intensity changes are converted into digital data and that is what reads the microprocessor.\n
Once the gyroscope sets in motion always maintains the orientation and it is oriented to the true north. The gyro gives us a precise orientation, it indicates the displacement on their axes and gives us the position regarding the exact starting point.\n
MENS (Microelectromechanical Systems, MEMS) refer to the electromechanical technology, their micrometer products and smaller scales (nanometer scale) are merged into nanoelectromechanical systems.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogiro3">PURPOSE OF GYROSCPE\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongiro3">The gyroscope give us the possibility to turn your screen.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogiro4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongiro4">The gyroscope measures the speed of rotation of the device around the x, y, and z axis.The values of the gyro data can be positive or negative. Looking at the origin of a position along the mid-axis positive, if the rotation occurs to the left side around the axis, the value is positive; Otherwise, the value is negative. We can also determine the direction of a gyroscope value.\n</string>
    <string name="titulomagne1">\nABOUT MAGNETOMETER\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionmagne1">It is an electronic component capable of measuring and quantifying the magnetic force of an object. I.e. it measures the magnetic field (µT).\n</string>
    <string name="titulomagne2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionmagne2">The main constituent is an electromagnet with an iron core with a coil of wire wrapped.\n
The magnetism changes depending on the location due to differences in (the magnetosphere) Earth\'s magnetic field and can be caused by the different nature of the rocks. Magnetometers are a frequent instrumental component of spacecraft that explores planets and for geological exploration for anticlinal structures.\n</string>
    <string name="titulomagne3">PURPOSE OF MAGNETOMETER\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionmange3">As well as a compass, it can serve as a metal detector.\n</string>
    <string name="titulomagne4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionmange4">The most important use of the magnetometer (described in table) in Android systems is to implement the compass.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloluz1">\nABOUT LIGHT SENSOR\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionluz1">It is an electronic device that responds to the change in light intensity. These sensors require a transmitter that generates light and a receptor component that receives light generated by the transmitter.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloluz2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionluz2">The light sensor includes a photoelectric transducer to convert the light into an electrical signal and may include electronics for signal conditioning and formatting the compensation signal.\n
The most common light sensor is Light Dependant Resistor. A LDR is basically a resistor that changes its resistance when light intensity changes. There are three types of photoelectric sensors, sensors for light barrier, reflection on mirror or reflection on objects.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloluz3">PURPOSE OF LIGHT SENSOR\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionluz3">Its function is to detect the intensity of the ambience light to adjust the screen brightness.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloluz4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionluz4">The system uses the ambient light sensor, described in the table, to detect the ambience lighting and automatically adjust the screen brightness to the appropriate level.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloprox1">\nABOUT PROXIMITY SENSOR\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionprox1">Se trata de un sensor capaz de medir la distancia entre el móvil y algún otro objeto. El sensor de proximidad se mide en centímetros (cm).\n</string>
    <string name="tituloprox2">HOW IT WORKS\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionprox2">These proximity sensors are based on an infra-red LED and an IR receiver. How does it work? It emits infra-red light and it detects if there is something very close to the device. In the case of a call, would be the ear.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloprox3">PURPOSE OF PROXIMITY SENSOR\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionprox3">When the device is approached to our ear to answer a call, the device turns off the backlight to save battery.\n
Besides, if we touch the screen by accident while we are on a call, nothing will happen because the proximity sensor locks the screen to prevent such errors.\n
Usually, if the device is dark it is almost imperceptible but if we look to the light we see it, if it has, of course.\n</string>
    <string name="tituloprox4">WHAT IT MEASURES\n</string>
    <string name="explicacionprox4">The proximity sensor provides the distance between the device and another object. The device can be used to detect if the user holds the device near (see table); therefore, you can determine if the user is on a call and if the screen can be turned off during the phone call\n</string>
    <string name="titulogps1">\n¿QUÉ ES EL GPS?\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongps1">Sistema Global de Navegación por Satélite (GNSS) que nos permite fijar a escala mundial la posición de un objeto, una persona, un vehículo o una nave.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogps2">¿CÓMO FUNCIONA EL GPS?\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongps2">El GPS se basa en la triangulación, un principio matemático que determina la posición exacta de un punto conociendo las distancias de éste a otros tres puntos de ubicación conocida. En teoría se usan tres satélites para determinar la posición, velocidad y altura a la que se encuentra el receptor.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogps3">¿PARA QUÉ SIRVE EL GPS?\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongps3">El GPS se puede usar para indicarnos trayectorias, rutas o como localización.\n</string>
    <string name="titulogps4">¿QUÉ DATOS NOS MUESTRA EL GPS?\n</string>
    <string name="explicaciongps4">Latitud y longitud.\n</string>
    <string name="gpsoff">GPS off</string>
    <string name="gpsbuscando">Searching GPS</string>
    <string name="gpssignal">GPS signal</string>
    <string name="gps">GPS</string>
    <string name="checkGps">Save data</string>
    <string name="latitud">Latitude</string>
    <string name="longitud">Longitude</string>
    <string name="ayuda">Help</string>
    <string name="ayuda11">En la pantalla principal se encuentran 2 opciones diferenciadas por botones:\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda12">Medición de Datos:\n
\tEn este apartado se mostraran los sensores con sus medidas.\n
Cargar Gráficas:\n
 \tEn este apartado se mostraran todos los ficheros con las gráficas guardadas.\n
Además de las dos opciones diferenciadas, en el botón CONFIGURACIÓN aparecen 4 opciones:\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda13">Sensores del dispositivo: en esta opción se recogen en un listado todos los sensores del dispositivo.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda14">\t\tNombre del sensor\n
\t\tConsumo de la batería\n
\t\tVersión\n
\t\tDistribuidor\n
\nConfiguración: en esta opción aparecen las preferencias de la aplicación, estas preferencias son:\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda15">\n\tIdioma: Se podrá elegir entre Auto, Español, Francés o Portugués.\n
\tDebajo de Configuración aparecen las opciones:\n
\t\t\tFrecuencias muestreo: se elige una frecuencia de los sensores, numero de muestras por segundo.\n
\t\t\tTemporizador: tiempo que transcurre desde que entramos en la pantalla de la gráfica hasta que empieza a grabar.\n
\t\t\tTiempo de grabación: se elige el tiempo que durará la grabación\n
Acerca de: En esta opción muestra la información de los autores y privacidad de la aplicación.\n
Ayuda: Ayuda de la aplicación.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda21">En esta pantalla se mostraran los sensores junto con sus mediciones. La pantalla se estructura:\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda22">\nBotones de información de los sensores:\n
\tAcelerómetro\n
\tGiroscopio\n
\tMagnetómetro\n
\tSensor proximidad\n
\tSensor Luz\n
\tGps\n
\nDebajo de cada botón de información de cada sensor hay:\n
\tOpción de guardar los datos: se marcara si se desea que se guarden los datos del sensor en un fichero Csv.\n
\tIcono Grafica: Este botón llevara a la representación de los sensores.\n
\tMuestra de datos: se mostraran las medidas tomadas por los sensores en tiempo real.\n
Además de las opciones en el botón preferencia aparecerán las opciones:\n
\tConfiguración aparecen las opciones:
\t\t\tFrecuencias muestreo- se elige una frecuencia de los sensores, numero de muestras por segundo.
\t\t\tTemporizador: tiempo que transcurre desde que entramos en la pantalla de la gráfica hasta que empieza a grabar.\n
\t\t\tTiempo de grabación- se elige el tiempo que durará la grabación\n
Ayuda: Ayuda de la aplicación.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda31">En esta pantalla aparece la representación de los datos de los sensores.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda32">Su estructura es la siguiente:\n
\tBotón empezar: se pulsara para iniciar la gráfica.\n
\tBotón Pausar/Parar: Se pulsara para detener o interrumpir la representación de la gráfica.\n
\tReiniciar: se pulsara para empezar una nueva representación de la grafica.\n
Debajo de los botones aparece:\n
\tMedidas: estas medidas podrán seleccionarse o no dependiendo de qué dato se desee mostrar.\n
\tREC: se mostrara en color verde si no se ha marcado guarda datos de la pantalla Medición de Datos, en caso de que la opción Guardar datos de la pantalla Medición de datos se halla seleccionado se mostrar de color rojo.\n
\tGPS señal: muestra el estado de la señal del Gps.\n
\tGráfica: se representan los datos que recoge el dispositivo móvil.\n
Además de estas opciones en la opción preferencias del sistema, una vez iniciada la representación de las mediciones, se podrán cambiar de un sensor a otro, compartirlo o guardarlo en formato CSV.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda41">En esta pantalla se muestran todos los ficheros guardados de las mediciones. En caso de seleccionar un fichero este mostrara la representación de las mediciones. Si se deja seleccionado durante un periodo prolongado de tiempo, el fichero podrá ser enviado mediante la opción que usted desee.\n
Si una vez seleccionado se quiere quitar de la lista a enviar solo tiene que pulsar prolongadamente sobre ese mismo archivo y quedará sin seleccionar.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda42">Se podrán seleccionar varios ficheros a la vez para enviarlos.\n</string>
    <string name="ayuda51">En las pantallas información de los sensores (giroscopio, acelerómetro, magnetómetro, sensor de luz, sensor proximidad y GPS) muestra la explicación de cada sensor. Cada pantalla está estructurada:\n
\t¿Qué es?: explicación de que mide y que es el sensor.\n
\t¿Cómo funciona?: explicación del funcionamiento del sensor.\n
\t¿Para qué sirve? : ejemplo de utilidad del sensor.\n
\t¿Datos que muestra?: medidas que toma en sensor en el dispositivo Android.\n</string>

</resources>